

Héctor Eduardo Sánchez Barrera

Highly skilled professional with 8 years of experience in frontend development and API architecture, specializing in technologies such as React, Angular, Node.js, and TypeScript. Proven experience in large-scale projects, including code refactoring to improve performance in tax audits and developing applications from scratch with microfrontends, such as the Necsus inventory management system.

CONTACT

- Mexico City
- 5570109033
- @ eduarsb4@gmail.com

SKILLS

- Professionalism and responsibility
- Time management
- Effective communication
- Teamwork
- Analytical approach
- Integration of web services
- Scalable projects
- Language: JS, TypeScript, NodeJS, PHP, Java, Bash
- Frameworks: React, Angular, Vue
- Design: CSS, SCSS, Bootstrap,
- Amazon AWS: Lambdas, Apigateway, Route53, SQS, SNS, EC2, S3, CloudWatch, CloudFormation, CloudFront
- Google: GCP y Apigee
- APIS: OpenApi 2.0 y 3.0, Cucumber, Postman
- Project management: Slack, Trello, Invision, Figma, Teams
- Version control: Git, GitLab, GitHub, Bitbucket
- CI/CD: Jenkins y Circle CI

DIPLOMAS

WORK HISTORY

Web developer

Grupo Salinas - CDMX

09/2022 - presente

- Planning of activities (layout, functionality, API consumption, implementation of functional requirements) according to established deadlines
- Creation of layouts according to screen designs
- Development of microfrontends in React, Angular, and Vue
- Implementation of code reuse strategies through generic components and libraries
- Participation in a training center for frontend developers
- Implementation of microservices with AWS Lambdas and Node.js

API Architect

06/2021 - 08/2022

Grupo Salinas - CDMX

- Deadline compliance control in API development.
- API documentation using OpenAPI contracts.
- Implementation of robustness and performance testing.
- Supervision and coordination of work in contract development.
- Implementation of policies in Apigee and AWS API Gateway.
- Planning and control in API deployments using Apigee and API Gateway.

Web developer

10/2018 - 05/2021

Iterando - CDMX

- Participation in requirement analysis and proposal of solutions for different client needs.
- Implementation of server configurations and deployment of web apps.
- Creation of various REST APIs for use by web applications.
- Collaboration in the development and maintenance of web projects based on JS.
- Implementation of reactive forms in Angular/React.
- Consumption of web services with Vue.js for statistical usage in projects.

Web developer

03/2018 - 09/2018

Fiscalía General del Esatdo de Veracruz - Xalapa

• Participation in integration with web services from the Vehicle Public Registry (REPUVE).

- Developing APIs with Google Cloud's Apigee API Platform
- API Development on Google Cloud's Apigee API Platform
- API Security on Google Cloud's Apigee API Platform
- API Design and Fundamentals of Google Cloud's Apigee API Platform
- Scrum Foundations Professional Certificate (SFPC).
- Angular: De cero a experto (Legacy)
- REDUX en Angular con NGRX: Desde las bases hasta la práctica
- Ionic 6+: Crear aplicaciones IOS, Android y PWAs con Angular
- MTA: Database Administration Fundamentals.
- CCNA Exploration.

- Implementation of design using Bootstrap, jQuery, HTML, JS, and CSS.
- The project aimed to integrate with an internal reporting system for the Attorney General's Office.

Web developer

08/2017 - 02/2018

Freelancer - Xalapa

- Maintenance of web pages and systems.
- Incorporation of new functionalities into various web systems.
- Web page layout with HTML, JS, and CSS.

Web developer

04/2015 - 07/2016

Hospital de Centro de Alta Especialidad (CAE) - Xalapa

- Implementation of a web platform to integrate small web systems of the hospital (payments, training, and courses).
- Implementation of a web system for payments and simple reports on hospital services.

EDUCATIONAL BACKGROUND

Master's degree: User-Centered Interactive Systems

Universidad Veracruzana

Bachelor's degree : Computer Science

Universidad Veracruzana

INTERESTS

I constantly seek opportunities to learn and grow, both personally and professionally. I am passionate about traveling and experiencing new cultures, which has taught me to appreciate diversity and adapt to different situations. In my free time, I enjoy activities that stimulate my creativity and logical thinking, such as video games and solving puzzles. I am a strong believer in teamwork and the importance of maintaining a healthy balance between work and personal life.